JOSEPH E. PERSICO PAPERS (APAP030) 1910-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- New York State Government Career, 1910-1981; 1; 9.8
  - Subject Files, 1947-1976; 1.2
    - Rockefeller Death Pamphlets, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Nelson Rockefeller: A Biography by Joe Alex Morris. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Nomination of Nelson A. Rockefeller of New York to be Vice President of the United States. Hearings Before the Committee on Rules and Administration. United States Senate, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings, 1968-1975; 1.3
    - Abortion, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Adirondack State Park, 1969-1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Arts, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Budget, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Campaigns, 1966-1974 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Cities, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Constitutional Convention, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Consumers, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Courts, 1969-1973 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Crime, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Death Penalty, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Drugs, 1966-1974 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Education, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Energy, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Environment, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Ford, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1967-1971 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Governors/ Wilson, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Health, 1968-1971 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Israel, Rockefeller Statements, 1968-1971 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Italian Americans, ca. 1970s (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Javits, Jacob K, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Jobs, 1967-1970 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Kennedy, Robert F, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Latin America (English and Spanish), 1969 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Levitt, Arthur, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Lindsay, John, 1967-1970 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Mass Transportation, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Medicaid, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Morrow, Hugh, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Motor Vehicles, 1970-1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - News Media, 1968-1973; Undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - New York City, 1967-1969 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Persico, Joseph E., 1969-1978 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Police, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Public Employees, 1960s-1973 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Republican Party, 1969-1975 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Riots, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller Family, Undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1971-1975 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - State Fair, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Speeches, 1968-1979 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - SUNY, 1968-1970 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Vietnam, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Voting, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Watergate, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Welfare, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - White House Mess, 1980; Undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Women, 1967-1973 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Rockefeller, Photographs, 1974 (Oversized 26, Folder 1)
- Publications, ca. 1930s-2001; 2; 6.4
  This series contains the notes, research material, interviews, drafts, news clippings, and memoranda which comprise Mr. Persico's files for his books.
  - Sub-series 1:Piercing the Reich, 1940-1979; 2.1; 1.4
    The Piercing the Reich subseries is primarily Persico's research material. The majority of the material is copies of declassified FBI files and the OSS War Report. The Writings subseries includes scripts for the History Channel documentaries "Piercing the Reich: The Deadly Deceivers" and "Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial" in the "Documentaries, Narration" folder. Additional material collected and created by Persico during the writing of Piercing the Reich was deposited by Persico at the Hoover Institution Library and Archives at Stanford University. The finding aid for this material is available online through the Online Archive of California.
    - Piercing the Reich, 1970s. FBI Declassified Files, 1940s-1970s; 2.1.1
      - Angleton, James (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Bancroft, Mary (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Bank, Aaron (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Boyd, Ann (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - British Intelligence (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Brittenham, Ray (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Bruce, David (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Burke, Mike (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Casey, William J. (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Cannoot, Ferdinand (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Chauefeur (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - CIA Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Chisel (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Copeland, Miles (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Crocus (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Dartmouth (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Dawes, Houseboat (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Deadwood (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Dillon (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - de Beaufort, Nam (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Doctor (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Downend (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Dupont (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - European Interviews Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - Fleisher, Henry (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - Gestapo (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Goldberg, Arthur (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Gould, Joseph (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Green - UP (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Grell, William (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Grimm, Kurt (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Hammer (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - Helms, Richard (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - Hoguet, Peter (Box 27, Folder 35)
      - Hood, Cornelia (Box 27, Folder 36)
      - Houston, Lawrence (Box 27, Folder 37)
      - Hyde, Henry (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - Haass, Walter (Box 27, Folder 39)
      - Issikides, Barbara (Box 27, Folder 40)
      - Italian Based Missions (Box 27, Folder 41)
      - Joan, Eleanor (Box 27, Folder 42)
      - Jolis, Albert (Box 27, Folder 43)
      - Junk, Robert (Box 27, Folder 44)
      - Karlow, Peter (Box 27, Folder 45)
      - Katz, Milton (Box 27, Folder 46)
      - Kirstein, Willi (Box 27, Folder 47)
      - Kolbe, Fritz (Box 27, Folder 48)
      - Laverge, Jan (Box 27, Folder 49)
      - Lowenstein (Box 27, Folder 50)
      - McCulloch (Box 27, Folder 51)
      - Meucke, Carl (Box 27, Folder 52)
      - Miller, Gerald (Box 27, Folder 53)
      - Molden, Fritz (Box 27, Folder 54)
      - Morgan, Henry (Box 27, Folder 55)
      - Oakes, John (Box 27, Folder 56)
      - OSS, History of (Box 27, Folder 57)
      - OSS Organization Charts (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - OSS Phone Book (Box 27, Folder 59)
      - Painter (Box 27, Folder 60)
      - Peenemunde (Box 27, Folder 61)
      - Perry, Hart (Box 27, Folder 62)
      - Photos (Box 27, Folder 63)
      - Pratt, George (Box 27, Folder 64)
      - Prester, Julio (Box 27, Folder 65)
      - Questions of Interviewees (Box 27, Folder 66)
      - Reddick, W.C. (Box 27, Folder 67)
      - Roman, Howard (Box 27, Folder 68)
      - Roosevelt, Kermit (Box 27, Folder 69)
      - Rubens, Pauley (Box 27, Folder 70)
      - Sichel, Peter (Box 27, Folder 71)
      - Simpson (Box 27, Folder 72)
      - Steiner, Herbert (Box 27, Folder 73)
      - Strahles, Carl (Box 27, Folder 74)
      - Sutton, Henry (Box 27, Folder 75)
      - Swiss, O.P.S. (Box 27, Folder 76)
      - Swiss Operations (Box 27, Folder 77)
      - Teper, Lazare (Box 27, Folder 78)
      - Thalberg, Hans (Box 27, Folder 79)
      - Thompson, Robert E.S. (Box 27, Folder 80)
      - Tofte, Hans (Box 27, Folder 81)
      - Training Agents (Box 27, Folder 82)
      - Turano, Anthony (Box 27, Folder 83)
      - Turnball, William (Box 27, Folder 84)
      - Ulmer (Box 27, Folder 85)
      - Ulsamer, Edgar (Box 27, Folder 86)
      - Van Arkel, Gerheart (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Van Dyke, Orpha (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Viertel, Peter (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Vuj Novich, George (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Watt, Richard (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Wynberg, Hans (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Yovel (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Piercing the Reich, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 8-13)
      OSS War Report (July 1949, reprinted 1976).
    - Piercing the Reich, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 8-13)
      OSS Operations in Europe, Africa, & the Mid-East, 1944-1945.
    - Piercing the Reich, Miscellaneous, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Piercing the Reich: American Spies in Nazi Germany, History Channel Documentary, 1976-1997 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series 2:Columbus, ca. 1980-1990; 2.2; 0.4
    The Columbus subseries includes Persico's research material, a book draft, and scripts and related material for theatrical performances.
    - Novel drafts (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Research (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Scripts & Performances (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
    - Theater Voices Presentation (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 3:My Enemy, My Brother, 1977; 2.3; 1 folder
    The subseries for My Enemy, My Brother contains only book reviews for Persico's first book.
    - My Enemy, My Brother. Book Reviews, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series 4:The Spiderweb, 1975-1983; 2.4; 1 folder
    - The Spiderweb. Miscellaneous, 1979-1983 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 5:Edward R. Murrow: An American Original, 1984-2001; 2.5; 0.2
    The Edward R. Murrow subseries includes administrative files, news clippings, material related to the promotion of the book, and correspondence about Persico's sale of rights to the book to filmmakers. Note that Persico donated most of his records related to this book to the Edward R. Murrow Center of Public Diplomacy at Tufts University.
    - Administrative, 1984-1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - News Clippings, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Promotion, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Movie Rights, 1997-2001 (Box 30, Folder 5A)
  - Sub-series 6:Casey: From the OSS to the CIA, 1989-1991; 2.6; 0.5
    The Casey subseries includes the author's research material and drafts of the biography of William Casey. According to Publishers Weekly, Persico worked from interviews and had exclusive access to Casey's papers. All of William Casy papers were returned to his widow, Sophia Casey.
    - Administrative Files, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Biography, News Clippings, Promotion, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Report, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Promotion, 1987-1992 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Casey-Sophia Issue, 1987-1991 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Draft (1-134) (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Draft (135-290) (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Draft (291-475) (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Draft (476-700) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Draft (701-866) (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Draft (867-1039) (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Draft (1040-end) (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Sub-series 7:Teacher, 1989-1990; 2.7; 0.1
    - Teacher, TV Script, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
      Research, Notes, and Administrative.
    - Teacher, TV Script, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      Drafts.
  - Sub-series 8:The Imperial Rockefeller, ca. 1970s-1985; 2.8; 0.4
    - Drafts (early), Undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Drafts, Undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Drafts (with correspondence), early 1980s-1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Interview Files. Interview List, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Interview Files. Albright, H., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Interview Files. Anbinder, P., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Interview Files. Armao, R., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Interview Files. Boyd, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Interview Files. Braun, T., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Interview Files. Canfield, S., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Interview Files. Cannon, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Interview Files. Canzeri, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Interview Files. Douglass, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Interview Files. Dunham, D., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Interview Files. Ekhof, W., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Interview Files. Hinman, G., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Interview Files. Hughes, E., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Interview Files. Humphries, G., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Interview Files. Hurd, T., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Interview Files. Lanigan, C., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Interview Files. Lelyveld, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Interview Files. Logue, E., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Interview Files. Marshall, A., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Interview Files. Morrow, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Interview Files. Rosenbaum, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Interview Files. Spad, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Interview Files. Wallison, P., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Interview Files. Watts, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Interview Files. Whiteman, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Interview Files. Whitman, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Interview Files. Wilson, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Interview Files. Zinker, L., 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Sub-series 9:Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, ca. 1930-2001; 2.9; 3 2 films
    The Nuremberg subseries includes the author's research material, manuscript drafts, correspondence, and promotion for each of the book's editions. Material related to the History Channel documentary Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial and the TNT television miniseries Nuremberg is also included in this subseries. Note that material related to Persico's promotion of both TNT's Nuremberg and the reissued paperback edition of the book are included in the folder of promotional records for 2000-2001. The Writings subseries includes scripts for the History Channel documentaries "Piercing the Reich: The Deadly Deceivers" and "Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial" in the "Documentaries, Narration" folder.
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, 1930s-1995; 2.9.1
      - American Heritage Article, 1992-1994 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Air Raid, 1945-1990s (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1994 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - US Army History Institute (Carlisle, PA), 1991-1994 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Research Materials, mostly 1940s (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Nuremberg Chronology, 1937-1946 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Clearances, 1991-1993 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Dimensions, (a Journal of Holocaust Studies), 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Directions, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Nuremberg Directory, printed 1991 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Pamphlets (Holocaust Museum & Memorial Council), 1990s (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Interview notes, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - Military History Quarterly, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - National Archives Docs (Records of War Crimes Trial Interrogations & Trial Proceedings), 1945-1949 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Photos (of the trial and the Holocaust), 1940s (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Photo credits, orders, & book cover, 1940s-1993 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Book Proposal, "Last Day at Nuremberg", undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Reunion materials, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - FDR Library materials, 1990s (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - Sources, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Syracuse University Library Information, 1990s (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Notes, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - Nuremberg Trial Telephone Directory, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Titles, undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Nuremberg Tourism Pamphlets, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - Trip folder, Washington, D.C., undated (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - Viking-Penguin (Publishing Co.), Correspondence and Notes, 1990-1993 (Box 32, Folder 27)
      - Yad Vashem Research, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - Research and Notes, 1940s-1990s; 6 folders (Box 32, Folder 29-31)
      - Nuremberg Reunion, 1995 (two years after the book's release) (Box 32, Folder 32)
      - Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial, History Channel Documentary, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, early 1990s; 2.9.2
      - Draft 1 Copy (1-165), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Draft 1 Copy (166-386), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Draft 1 Copy (387-574), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Draft 1 Copy (575-748), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Draft 1 Copy (749-end), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (1-188), early 1990s (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (189-324), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 1)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (325-500), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 2)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (501-674), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 3)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (675-end), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 4)
      - Draft unspecified (1-136), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 5)
      - Draft unspecified (137-327), early 1990s (Box 33A, Folder 6)
      - Draft unspecified (328-511), early 1990s (Box 33B, Folder 1)
      - Draft unspecified (512-645), early 1990s (Box 33B, Folder 2)
      - Draft unspecified (646-end), early 1990s (Box 33B, Folder 3)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, 1993; 2.9.3
      - Photos of the Holocaust & the Nuremberg Trial, ca. early 1940s-1946 (Box 33C, Folder 1)
      - Draft II (pgs 1-101) (Box 33C, Folder 2)
      - Draft II (pgs 101-200) (Box 33C, Folder 3)
      - Draft II (pgs 201-300) (Box 33C, Folder 4)
      - Draft II (pgs 301-400) (Box 33C, Folder 5)
      - Draft II (pgs 401-500) (Box 33C)
      - Draft II (pgs 501-600) (Box 33C, Folder 7)
      - Draft II (pgs 601-700) (Box 33C, Folder 8)
      - Draft II (pgs 701-783) (Box 33C, Folder 9)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, 2.9.4
      - Book Reviews, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Film, Photographs, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Film, Production, 1993-2000 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Manuscript Editing, 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Promotion, 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Promotion, 2000-2001 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Screenplay Notes, ca. 1995 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Shooting Script, 1999 July 20 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Thomas F. Leahy Panel, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Unidentified Nuremberg War Crimes Trial Book, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - War Crimes, News Clippings, 1993-1995 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Nuremberg, TNT Television Movie, Based on Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, VHS, 2000 July 16
    - Joseph E. Persico on the Liz Bishop Show discussing Nuremberg, VHS, 2000 July 16
  - Sub-series 10:Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage, 2001; 2.10; 0.2
    This subseries includes a review of Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage from The New York Times Book Review. Artwork for the review by Thomas Powers was featured on the cover of the issue.
    - Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage, Book Review, The New York Times Book Review, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-2003; 3; 1.17
  The texts, drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material is available for speeches and other non-book writings of Persico.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Sub-series 1: Speeches, 1975-2002; 3.1; 0.17
    The texts, drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material is available for some of the speeches and lectures given by Persico. Also included in this subseries is material related to panels Persico participated in on topics related to his publications. Note that additional material related to Persico's speeches is available in the Correspondence series as the creator did not always separately file that correspondence.
    - American Swiss Foundation, Speaking Engagement, Correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Commencement Address, Gloversville High School, Gloversville, NY, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Commencement Address, University at Albany, SUNY, Albany, NY, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Dartmouth, Montgomery Fellows Lecture, Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Greek Public Television ERT, Program about Colin Powell, Correspondence, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Harry S. Truman Presidential Library, Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - The Rockefellers, American Experience Television Documentary, 1998-2000 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Speakers Project, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1991-2002 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - University at Albany Veterans Project, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series 2: Writings, 1958-2003; 3.2; 1 cubic foot
    The Writings subseries includes drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material available for the non-book writings of Persico. Persico has published many articles on historical topics in publications such as American Heritage as well as book reviews and opinion ("op-ed") pieces for newspapers. A few folders of research material are also included in this series. Also included in this subseries is research material assembled for writing projects that did not result in a publication of a book and an unpublished manuscript for a novel, The Fornix. The "Documentaries, Narration" folder also includes scripts for the History Channel documentaries "Piercing the Reich: The Deadly Deceivers" and "Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial".
    - Benjamin Franklin, Research Material, ca. 2002 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Bogliasco Foundation Residency, 1997-2002 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Armand Hammer: The Untold Story, "Lonely at the Top", 1996 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Battleground Berlin: CIA vs. KGB in the Cold War, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America- Stalin Era, "The Kremlin Connection", 1998-1999 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Sword and the Shield, "Secrets from the Lubyanka", 1999 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Private Life of Kim Philby: The Moscow Years, "Out in the Cold", 2000 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, A Convenient Spy: Wen Ho Lee and the Politics of Nuclear Espionage and My Country Versus Me: The First-Hand Account by the Los Alamos Scientist Who was Falsely Accused of Being a Spy, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Intelligence in War: Knowledge of the Enemy from Napoleon to Al-Qaeda, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, A Look Over My Shoulder: A Life in the Central Intelligence Agency, "Company Man", 2003 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Book Reviews, 1978-2000 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Bridge to the Past", Sleepy Hollow Restorations, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Documentaries, Narration, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Edward R. Murrow and William J. Casey, Documentary Proposals, 1995 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Erie Canal, Research Material, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "The Flight of the Enola Gay"Modern Maturity, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - The Fornix, ca. 1980 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - The Fornix, ca. 1980 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "The Great Gun Merchant"American Heritage, 1974 August (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "How much Legal Protection does New York State give the Consumer?" Consumer Counsel to the Governor, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Influenza Epidemic of 1918, Persico Article and Documentary, 1996-1998 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "An Interview with John Huston"American Heritage, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - "The Last Days of the Third Reich"American Heritage, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - "The Making of a War Criminal".Dimensions, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Marilyn Monroe and Joe DiMaggio, Book Proposal, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1960s-1976 (Box 45, Folder 26)